vincenzorm117@gmail.com (954)778-0251

# Vincenzo Marconi

Orlando, FL 32804

github.com/vincenzorm117 romolo.io

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am a Software Engineer with 3 years of professional experience, a background in mathematics, and specializing in full stack applications and extensions. I'm currently seeking a professional opportunity as a Software Engineer that will challenge and provide me growth within my development career.

#### **SKILLS**

- **Proficient** in JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, Python3, Node.js, Express Framework, Angular 2+, Command line tools, HTML, SASS/LESS/CSS, JSON, C#, and Git.
- Working knowledge in AWS, React, Unix Shell Scripting, Alexa Skills Skit, Docker, Java, C++, C, PHP, MySQL, Redis, Chrome Extensions, Apache, Nginx, MS-SQL and Swift.
- **Experience** in Heroku, Symfony Framework, and Objective-C.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Alaso USA Inc. Contracting

Sep. 2018 - Present

 Developing and testing full stack applications and systems to automate and optimize warehouse operations ranging from utilities as printing labels to measuring production output per machine and warehouse employee.

## **FCFMN Construction Tracking Contracting**

Feb. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Built a full stack web application to track construction sites for the construction contractors of the FCFMN organization using Node.js, MongoDB, Redis, Google Cloud Services, Angular 5, and WebSockets.

## Studio Birdsall LLC Employment

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2018

- Managed and developed custom web applications and solutions for eCommerce and corporate clients on WordPress,
  Magento, and Shopify using JavaScript, Python, PHP, HTML, and SCSS/CSS.
- Notable projects include: hivelocity.com, makr.com, indigoandcotton.com, chaptex.com, and armatureworks.com.

#### MyMailbox GPG2 Inc. Contracting

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2017

 Designed and developed all of the software for a physical smart mailbox notification system that works with Particle's IOT micro-controller cloud systems, delivering notifications through Twilio with Node.js.

#### BrandCo LLC Employment

Mar. 2015 - Aug 2016

- Built a full stack Email Tracking System called Cue supported on Chrome, Firefox, Outlook and iOS with a small development team that reported directly to employer.
- Developed a Client Review System that monitored and distributed client satisfaction per client-employee interaction.

#### **Disney Professional Internship**

May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Developed a booking metrics application that increased metric gathering and rendering by over 100%.

#### Systems Software Teacher's Assistant

Aug. 2014 - Dec. 2015

Tutored compiler and OS concepts and built an auto grader that decreased grading time by 50%.

#### Perceptron Visualizer Project

May 2014

• Developed a Neural Net, and a Perceptron GUI using Swift 2 and Cocoa for a presentation to help illustrate the workings and limitation of Perceptrons. For more info see my github repo.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Central Florida**

Sep. 2011 - May 2016

- Graduated May 2016 with a Bachelors in Computer Science and a Minor in Mathematics.
- Placed in 1st on the Putnam Mathematical Competition two years in a row in UCF.
- Received Honorable Mentions for my team's submission to the COMAP 2015 Math Modelling Competition.
- Placed in 5th at the local Deloitte Programming Competition with a small team.